dubaitourism.ae 2019-04-04

# About DTCM - Visit Dubai Privacy Policy

_Last modified: 14th August 2018 view archivedversions._

**Background**

Department of Tourism and Commerce Marketing (“ **DTCM** ”) is an entity established pursuant to Law No. 1 of 1997 and having its principal address at P.O. Box 594, Dubai, United Arab Emirates.

DTCM is the principal authority for the planning, supervision, development and marketing of tourism in Dubai. We also market and promote Dubai’s commerce sector and are responsible for the licensing and classification of all tourism services, including hotels establishments, tour operators, travel agents and all other tourism services. You can find out more about us at: https://www.visitdubai.com/en/department-of-tourism/about-dtcm.

DTCM and its affiliates, including, but not limited to, Dubai Festivals and Retail Establishment, Dubai Corporation for Tourism and Commerce Marketing, Dubai Business Events and Dubai Calendar (collectively, “ **Dubai Tourism** ”, “ **We** ”, “ **we** ”, “ **our** ” or “ **us** ”) are committed to providing excellent service to all customers, including respecting their concerns about privacy and taking the relevant measures to safeguard their personal data in accordance with applicable data protection legislation. We have provided this Privacy Policy to help you, the user, understand how we collect, use and protect your information when you visit and use any of Dubai Tourism’s websites (including, without limitation, www.visitdubai.com) and any microsites and tools contained therein (our “ **Websites** ”), mobile applications (including, without limitation, the Visit Dubai and Dubai Calendar mobile applications) and any tools contained therein (our “ **Mobile Applications** ”), social media pages, and other technological platforms in whatever form (together referred to as our “ **Platforms** ”), and how that information will be treated. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your information and how we will treat it.

This Privacy Policy should be read together with our terms of use www.visitdubai.com/en/terms-of-use and any other documents referred to in it. 

Please note that we will ask for your consent before using information for a purpose other than those that are set out in this Privacy Policy. 

Your privacy matters to us so if you have any questions please contact us at [privacy@dubaitourism.ae](mailto:privacy@dubaitourism.ae). 

**Key Terms**

This Privacy Policy uses the following key terms:

  * **Browser web storage:** enables websites to store data in a browser on a device. When used in "local storage" mode, it enables data to be stored across sessions (for example, so that the data are retrievable even after the browser has been closed and reopened). One technology that facilitates web storage is HTML 5.
  * **Non-personally identifiable information:** information that is recorded about users so that it no longer reflects or references an individually identifiable user.
  * **Personal data:** any information which you provide to us which directly or indirectly personally identifies you, such as your name, email address, billing information, credit card information, or other data which can be reasonably linked to such information by Dubai Tourism, such as information we associate with any accounts you may hold with Dubai Tourism.
  * **Sensitive personal data:** special categories of personal data, specifically, information about your race, ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, any trade union membership you hold, genetics, biometrics (where used for ID purposes), health, sex life or sexual orientation.

**Acceptance and Management of Personal Data**

To assist you in managing your personal data, we will provide you with a copy of all personal data we have about you should you request it. Please contact us at [privacy@dubaitourism.ae](mailto:privacy@dubaitourism.ae) to do this.

In addition, you are able to update and amend your personal data at any time, or request us to remove you and your personal data collected electronically from our database(s) by emailing [privacy@dubaitourism.ae](mailto:privacy@dubaitourism.ae). 

**Collection and Uses made of the information**

We collect and use information held about you in the following ways: 

_Information you give to us:_ For example, some of our services may require you to sign-up and create an account or provide personal data. In such circumstances, we’ll request personal data, like your name, email address, nationality, age, country of residence, telephone number or credit card to store with your account.

We may use this information: 

  * to provide you with the information, products and services that you request from us (including Dubai Calendar – see "Dubai Calendar" section below for more information);
  * to respond to your questions, comments and requests;
  * where you have indicated your consent, to provide you, or permit selected third parties to provide you, with additional services and/or information about additional services that may interest you (see “Marketing” section below for more information);
  * to notify you about changes to one or all of our Platforms;
  * to ensure that content from our Platforms is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your device; and/or
  * for the uses set forth in the “Information we collect about you” section below.

_Information we collect about you:_ We collect information about the services that you use and how you use them. This information may include (i) internet protocol (IP) address, (ii) device-specific information (such as your hardware model, operating system version, unique device identifiers, and mobile network information including phone number), (iii) device event information such as crashes, system activity, hardware settings, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request and referral URL, (iv) cookies or similar technologies that may uniquely identify your browser or any of your accounts on our Platforms, (v) information (including personal data) locally on your device using mechanisms such as browser web storage (including HTML 5) and application data caches. We may also collect and process location information when you use any of our Platforms through various technologies such as Wi-Fi access points and cell towers and IP addresses. 

When information is associated with any of your accounts on our Platforms, we treat it as personal data. For more information on your rights regarding your personal data please refer to the “Your Rights” section. For information on how to exercise your rights please refer to the “Contact us with Your Questions and Comments” section. 

We may use this information:

  * for the uses set forth in the “Information you give to us” section above;
  * to administer our Platforms and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes;
  * to offer you tailored content;
  * to improve our Platforms to ensure that content is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your device;
  * to allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so;
  * as part of our efforts to keep our Platforms safe and secure;
  * to measure or understand the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver relevant advertising to you; 
  * for market research and analysis purposes; and/or
  * where you have indicated your consent, to make suggestions and recommendations to you and other users of our Platforms about goods or services that may interest you or them (see “Marketing” section below for more information).

_Information we receive from other sources:_ We may combine information we receive from others sources with information you give to us and information we collect about you. We may use this information and the combined information for the purposes set out above (depending on the types of information we receive).

**How we collect personal data**

We collect your personal data directly from you unless it is unreasonable or impractical to do so. We do this in a number of ways including:

  * through your access and use of our Platforms or sending SMS/MMS to us;
  * when you enter into a competition or promotion;
  * through someone else who has provided us with your information (e.g. a gift subscription);
  * during conversations between you and our representatives; and/or
  * when you complete an application or subscription.

We may also collect personal data from third parties including:

  * third party companies such as credit reporting agencies, law enforcement agencies and other government entities;
  * advertisers;
  * mailing lists;
  * recruitment agencies; and/or
  * contractors and business partners.

Any personal data we collect about you will only be retained for as long as it takes for the purposes for which such information is required to be completed. If we no longer need to use or disclose your personal data for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy and we are not legally required to retain that information, then we will take reasonable steps to destroy your personal data or ensure it is rendered anonymous (i.e. turned into non-personally identifiable information).

**Marketing**

Where you have indicated your consent, we (and permitted third parties) may contact you for direct marketing purposes via post, telephone, email, SMS/MMS, push notifications, and social media channels such as Facebook, Instagram, Twitter and WhatsApp. 

This marketing may relate to:

  * additional products and services we (or permitted third parties) feel may interest you; 
  * information about other goods and services we offer that are similar to those that you have already used or enquired about; and
  * upcoming events, promotions and new products/services or other opportunities as well as those of selected third parties.

If you are an existing customer, we will only contact you by electronic means without seeking your consent in advance (including but not limited to telephone, e-mail, SMS/MMS, push notifications, and social medial channels such as Facebook, Instagram, Twitter and WhatsApp) with information about services similar to those which were the subject of a previous dealing with you.

If you no longer wish to receive marketing communications from us you may unsubscribe by following the unsubscribe link in our email communications or by requesting us to remove you and your personal data collected electronically from our database(s) by emailing [privacy@dubaitourism.ae](mailto:privacy@dubaitourism.ae).

**Internet Protocol (IP) Address**

An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your device every time you browse the internet. When you visit our Platforms, the server used by our web host will make a record of your IP Address, together with the date and time of your visit, the type of Internet Browser you use and the URL of any other websites that referred you to our Platforms. 

We may also log IP addresses to analyse trends, administer our Platforms, track user movements, and gather broad demographic information.

**Cookies**

In some cases we may also collect your personal data through the use of cookies. When you access our Websites, we may send a “cookie” (which is a small summary file containing a unique ID number) to your device. This enables us to recognize your device and customise the online experience. It also helps us keep track of services you view, so that we can send you news about those services. We also use cookies to measure traffic patterns, to determine which areas of our Websites have been visited, and to measure transaction patterns in the aggregate. We use this to research our users’ habits so that we can improve our services. If you do not wish to receive cookies, you can set your browser so that your device does not accept them. You can find out how to do this, and find more information about cookies, at [www.allaboutcookies.org](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/). 

We may also collect anonymous data (which is not personal data) relating to your activity on our Websites (including IP addresses) via cookies, or we may collect information from you in response to a survey. We generally use this information to report statistics, analyse trends, administer our services, diagnose problems and target and improve the quality of our services. To the extent this information does not constitute personal data because it does not identify you or anyone else, we may use this information for any purpose and by any means whatsoever.

In addition to the express notice provided on our Websites when you first visit, your continued use of our Websites is your acceptance of our continued use of cookies on our Websites.

**Links to Other Websites**

We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites or services linked to or from our Websites, including the information or content contained therein or the data collection practices or privacy policies therein. Please remember that when you use a link to go from our Websites to another website, our Privacy Policy does not apply to third-party websites or services. Your browsing and interaction on any third-party websites or service, including those that have a link or advertisement on our Websites, are subject to that third party’s own rules and policies. In addition, you agree that we are not responsible and we do not have control over any third-parties that you authorize to access your user content. If you are using a third-party website or service (like Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, Instagram, or Google groups etc.) and you allow such a third-party access to your user content you do so at your own risk. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information we collect by other means (including offline) or from other sources other than through our Platforms.

**Information we share**

We do not share personal data with companies, organizations and individuals outside of Dubai Tourism unless one of the following circumstances applies: 

  * **With your consent**  
We will share personal data with companies, organizations or individuals outside of Dubai Tourism (and the parties and bodies referenced in this section of the Privacy Policy) when we have your consent to do so.
  * **For external processing**  
We provide personal data to our affiliates or other trusted businesses or persons to process it for us, based on our instructions and in compliance with our Privacy Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.
  * **Sharing with our partners**  
We may share non-personally identifiable information publicly and with our partners – like publishers, advertisers or connected websites. For example, we may share information publicly to show trends about the general use of our services.
  * **Where required by applicable law**  
We will disclose personal data when required by any applicable law, or in good faith believe such action is necessary or desirable to comply with the applicable laws, or to protect or defend the rights or property of Dubai Tourism, our Platforms, or their users.
  * **With selected third parties**  
We may disclose your personal data to third parties in the following circumstances: 
    * in the event that Dubai Tourism sells or buys any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets;
    * if Dubai Tourism or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it will be one of the transferred assets;
    * agents, service providers and third parties who provide services relating to the purpose for which the personal data is collected including data processing services, whether or not such agents, service providers and third parties are based in the UAE; 
    * any person who is under a duty of confidentiality and has undertaken to keep such data confidential; and
    * if you use our Dubai Calendar service (in accordance with the "Dubai Calendar" section of this Privacy Policy below). 

**Dubai Calendar**

Dubai Calendar is the official calendar of year-round events happening in Dubai, where event organizers may list events and ticket sellers may offer tickets for such events for users of the Dubai Calendar to purchase.

If you use our Dubai Calendar services, we will collect, use and otherwise process your information in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy. More specifically, we will: 

  * collect your personal data when you sign-up to the service;
  * use and otherwise process your personal data in order to provide you with the service; and
  * disclose your personal data to third party event organizers and ticket sellers in order for these third parties to provide you with a service.

**Where we store your personal data**

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, stored and otherwise processed on servers located outside the country in which you reside and which may be based in locations both within and outside of the UAE.

**Your Rights**

If you are located in the European Union, under the EU General Data Protection Regulation you have a number of rights with regard to your personal data that we must comply with. The rights you have are:

  * The right to be informed  
You have the right to be informed about the collection and use of your personal data by us or, on our behalf, by a third party. 
  * The right to access  
You have the right to obtain from us confirmation as to whether or not your personal data is being processed and, if so, the right to access that personal data. This right does not apply where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of another person. 
  * The right to rectification  
You have the right to request that we correct any inaccurate personal data and we must comply in a timely manner. Taking into account the purposes of the processing, you shall have the right to have incomplete personal data completed. 
  * The right to erasure  
You have the right to request the erasure of your personal data, in our possession, in a timely manner. 
  * The right to restrict processing  
You have the right to request the restriction of use of your personal data, where the data is not being used for the purpose it was collected for.
  * The right to object to processing  
You have the right to object at any time to our use of your personal data where that use is based on legitimate interest* or the public interest. *‘Legitimate interest’ is a lawful basis for processing personal data where (i) the use of data has a limited impact on you, (ii) you should reasonably expect us to use your data in such a way, or, (iii) where we do not deem it appropriate to contact you with disruptive consent requests.
  * The right to data portability  
Where you have provided personal data for us to use with your consent* or as required for us to fulfil our contractual obligations to you, you have the right to receive personal data that you have provided from us in a structured, commonly-used format in order for you to provide that personal data to another organisation for use as you so wish. This right does not apply where we are using the personal data to carry out a public duty (e.g. security or compliance).  
_*This includes sensitive personal data such as biometric, health or political or religious beliefs provided with your explicit consent._
  * The right to complain to a supervisory authority  
You have the right to submit a formal written complaint to a regulator who can resolve any complaints regarding the transfer of personal data that we cannot resolve with you directly.
  * The right to withdraw consent  
You have the right to inform us that you no longer wish us to collect, store, or use your personal data, where there is not a business or legal reason for us to do so.

To exercise these rights you will need to contact us with your request. Details of how to contact us are available in the “Contact us with Your Questions and Comments” section below.

**Contact us with Your Questions and Comments**

If you elect to contact us with any questions, comments or requests using one of the online forms that form part of our Platforms, you will need to provide your full name, telephone number and e-mail address so that we can be sure to be able to contact you. Depending on which online form you complete, you will be given the opportunity to provide additional information that will allow us to serve you better, although the additional information might not be required in order for you to complete and submit the online form.

If you would like more information on how we handle your personal data or would like to make a request relating to one of your rights above you can:

  * Email us at: [privacy@dubaitourism.ae](mailto:privacy@dubaitourism.ae)
  * Fill out an online form: www.visitdubai.com/en/suggestions-and-complaints. 

**Opt-Out**

You may unsubscribe from marketing email communication sent by our Platforms at any time by following the unsubscribe link in our email communications (see “Marketing” section above) or by requesting us to remove you and your personal data collected electronically from our database(s) by emailing privacy@dubaitourism.ae. 

You may also set your browser to block all cookies, including cookies associated with our Platforms, or to indicate when a cookie is being set by us. However, it’s important to remember that many of our Platforms may not function properly if your cookies are disabled. For example, we may not remember your language preferences.

**Security**

We will take all reasonable steps to protect the personal data that we hold from misuse, loss, or unauthorized access, including by means of firewalls, password access and secure servers. In particular, we review our information collection, storage and processing practices, including physical security measures, to guard against unauthorized access to systems, and restrict access to personal data to our employees, contractors and agents who need to know that information in order to process it for us, and who are subject to strict contractual confidentiality obligations and may be disciplined or terminated if they fail to meet these obligations.

Unfortunately, there is always risk involved in sending information through any channel over the internet. You send information over the internet entirely at your own risk. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted over the internet and we do not warrant the security of any information, including personal data, which you transmit to us over the internet. 

If you suspect any misuse or loss of, or unauthorized access to, your personal data, please let us know immediately.

**Compliance and cooperation with regulatory authorities**

We regularly review our compliance with our Privacy Policy. When we receive formal written complaints, we will contact the person who made the complaint to follow up. We work with the appropriate regulatory authorities, including local data protection authorities, to resolve any complaints regarding the transfer of personal data that we cannot resolve with our users directly. 

**Privacy Policy Changes**

In the future, we may revise or amend this Privacy Policy at any time by amending this page. All changes will be made here so you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information and whether we will disclose it to anyone. Some of the provisions contained in this Privacy Policy may also be superseded by provisions or notices published elsewhere on our Websites.

We will inform you of any changes to the Privacy Policy via pop-up, email communication or a push notification via our Mobile Applications.

**Conclusion**

Your privacy concerns are important to us. We hope this Privacy Policy has been helpful to you.

**Questions Concerning this Privacy Policy**

If you have questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please feel free to e-mail us at [privacy@dubaitourism.ae](mailto:privacy@dubaitourism.ae).
